So you just learned about what's probably the most important
你已经学习了本次统计学任务中
piece of math with this task, in statistics, called Bayes Rule.
最重要的数学内容 即贝叶斯法则
It's invented by Thomas Bayes, who was a British mathematician and
18 世纪英国数学家和长老会牧师托马斯·贝叶斯 (Thomas Bayes)
a Presbyterian minister in the 18th century.
发明了这一法则
Bayes rule is usually stated as follows.
贝叶斯法则通常解释如下
P(A|B) where B is the evidence and
P(A|B) 其中 B 是证据
A is the variable we care about,
A 是我们关注的变量
is P(B|A) * P(A) / P(B).
P(A|B) = P(B|A) * P(A) / P(B)
This expression is called the Likelihood,
这种表达称为似然性
this is called the Prior and this is called the Marginal Likelihood.
这是先验 这是边缘似然
The expression over here is called the posterior.
这里的表达称为后验
The interesting thing is the way the probabilities are reworded.
有趣的是概率重新改写的方式
Say we have evidence B.
例如我们有证据 B
We know about B.
B 是已知的
But we really care about the variable A.
我们真正关注的是变量 A
So, example B is a test result.
例如 B 是检查结果
We don't care about the test result as we much as we
我们并不那么关注检查结果
care about the fact of whether we have cancer or not.
而是更关注我们是否患癌的事实
This diagnostic reasoning,
这个诊断推理
which is from evidence to its causes,
从证据到原因
is turned upside down by Bayes rule into a causal reasoning,
经过贝叶斯法则完全颠倒 成为因果推理
which is given hypothetically we knew the cause,
通过假设的形式我们了解原因
what would be the probability of the evidence we just observed.
成为我们观察到证据的概率
But to correct for this inversion we have to multiply by the prior
不过为了纠正这种逆转 我们可以首先
of the cause to be the case in the first place in this having cancel or
乘以事件原因的先验 在这个例子中是否患癌
not, and divide it by the probability of the evidence, POE.
然后除以证据的概率 P(E)
Which is often expanded using the field of total probability as follows.
经常使用全概率的场进行扩充 如下所示
The probability of B is the sum of all the probabilities of the condition on a,
B 的概率 P(B) 等于
lower caps a, times the probability of A=a.
P(B|A=a) P(A=a) 的总和
This is total probability.
这就是全概率
So let's apply this to the cancer case,
我们把它应用在癌症例子中
and say we really care about whether they have cancer, which is our cause
我们真正关注他们是否患癌
conditioned on the evidence that is the result of this hidden cause.
即原因依赖于证据 证据是这个原因的结果
In this case, the positive test result.
在这个例子中是阳性检查结果
Let's just plug in the numbers.
然后我们加入数字
Our likelihood is the probability of seeing a positive test result given
似然性是发现阳性检查结果且已患癌的概率 P(+|C)
that they had cancer multiplied by the prior probability of having cancer over
乘以患癌的先验概率 P(C)
probability of the positive test result and that is according to
除以得到阳性检查结果的概率 P(+)
the tables we looked at before, 0.9 times a prior of 0.01 over.
根据我们之前看到的表格 应是 0.9 * 0.01
Now we're going to expand this variable here,
然后我们要扩大这个变量
equal to the total probability which gives us 0.9 times 0.01.
等于全概率 即 0.9 * 0.01
It's the probability(+) given that we do have cancer.
这是 P(+) 且已患癌的概率
So the probability of plus, given that we don't have cancer,
P(+) 且没有患癌的概率 是0.2
is 0.2, but the prior is 0.99.
但先验是 0.99
So if you plug in the numbers we know about,
所以如果加入我们已知的数字
we get 0.009 / 0.009 + 0.198.
得到 0.009 * 0.009 + 0.198
Is approximately 0.0434
约为 0.0434
which is the number we solved before.
这就是我们之前解决得到数字
[BLANK_AUDIO]最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
[无背景音]最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6